A Guide to the Crowder Family Papers, 1876-1976 (bulk 1920-1960)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Crowder Family Papers, 1876-1976 (bulk 1920-1960)
The Library of Virginia
44451
16.5 cubic feet (37 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Connecticut Historical Society, Hartford, CT.
Biographical Information
Bouldin Crowder was born on 7 December 1879. He was the son of Nelson Harper Crowder (1848-1923) and Angelina Dabney Bouldin (1847-1929). He married Elizabeth McLean on 30 August 1905. She was born on 8 April 1884 in Charlotte County, Virginia, and was the daughter of Dr. E. Patrick McLean (1843-1905) and Annie Cunningham (1845-1928). Bouldin and Bess Crowder lived in Clarksville, Mecklenburg County, Virignia where he owned and operated clothing and general store with his brother under the name "Crowder Brothers." They had three children: Elizabeth Bouldin Crowder (1908-1998) married 1) Charles B. H. Vaill (1904-1953) in 1937 and 2) Ralph Leroy Harlow (1885-1960) in 1958. Eleanor Marian Crowder (1911-1995) married Louis Napoleon Moore, Jr. in 1935 in South Hill, Virginia. Bouldin MacLean Crowder (b. 1913) married Mary Elizabeth Ward (1914-2009) in 1940. Bouldin Crowder died in July 1967. His wife Bess died on 9 December 1964. They are buried in Oakhurst Cemetery in Clarksville, Virginia.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1876-1976, of the Crowder family of Mecklenburg County, Virginia, and Connecticut, Massachusetts, and New York. Includes correspondence, subject files, Crowder Brothers store records, papers relating to Elizabeth (Crowder) Vaill Harlow's work as a microbiologist and real estate broker, publications, and newspapers. The bulk of the collection covers the period 1920 to 1960.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
I. Correspondence.
II. Subject Files.
III. Crowder Brothers Store Records.
IV. Microbiology Files.
V. Real Estate Broker Files.
VI. Publications.
VII. Newspapers.
Contents List
- Series I. Correspondence, 1880, 1890-1973., Extent: 19 boxes. (Box 1-19)
  The earliest letters in the collection are written to Elizabeth "Bess" McLean Crowder (1884-1964) from relatives in Pennsylvania, as well as from Bouldin Crowder (1879-1067) prior to their marriage, and afterwards while he was employed by the Internal Revenue Service and living in Alexandria, Virginia. There are also letters from her sister Annie Belle McLean (b. 1889) while she was a student at the State Normal School in Farmville, Virginia. The correspondence from 1925-1935 consists of letters between Bess and Bouldin Crowder and their daughters Elizabeth Bouldin Crowder (1908-1998), while she was attending the North Carolina College for Women in Greensboro, and Eleanor Marian Crowder (1911-1995), while was a student at The College of William and Mary. There are numerous letters written to Elizabeth and Eleanor from friends who were attending other schools, including Duke University, Hampden-Sydney College, Wake Forest University, Queens Chicora College, Danville Military Institute, and Randolph-Macon College. The majority of the post-1935 correspondence is to and from Elizabeth (Crowder) Vaill Harlow while she was living in Winsted, Connecticut and Framingham Centre, Massachusetts.
  Subjects covered in the letters include family news, health, births, marriages, and deaths, courtship, student life, including grades, classes, vacations, roomates and other classmates, and social life, including attending movies, concerts, dances, plays, and other events. There is a good deal of correspondence relating to Elizabeth (Crowder) Vaille Harlow's work as a radiological technician and microbiologist in various hospitals and laboratories in Connecticut, New York and Virginia, and later as a real estate broker in Framingham Centre, Massachussetts.
  Chronological.
  - 1880. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1890. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1898. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1899. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1900. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1901. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1902. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1903. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1904 (January-October). (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1904 (November-December). (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1905 (January-February). (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1905 (March-December). (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1906 (January-May). (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1906 (June-December). (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1907. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1908. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 1909. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 1910. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 1911. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 1912. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 1913. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 1914. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 1915. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 1916. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 1917. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 1918. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 1919. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 1920. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1921. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1922. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1923. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1924 (January-June). (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1924 (July-August). (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1924 (September). (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1924 (October 1-15). (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1924 (October 16-30). (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1924 (November). (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1924 (December). (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 1925 (January-May). (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 1925 (June-July). (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 1925 (August). (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1925 (September-October). (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 1925 (November). (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 1925 (December). (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 1926 (January). (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 1926 (February-March). (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 1926 (April-June). (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 1926 (July-August). (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 1926 (September). (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 1926 (October-December). (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 1927 (January-March). (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 1927 (Apri-June). (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - 1927 (July). (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 1927 (August-September). (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 1927 (October-December). (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 1928 (January). (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 1928 (February-March). (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 1928 (April). (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 1928 (May). (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 1928 (June-July). (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 1928 (August). (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 1928 (September 1-12). (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 1928 (September 13-17). (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - 1928 (September 18-22). (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - 1928 (September 23-30). (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - 1928 (October 1-9). (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 1928 (October 10-16). (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 1928 (October 17-25). (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 1928 (October 26-31). (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 1928 (November 1-9). (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 1928 (November 10-19). (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 1928 (November 20-30). (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - 1928 (December 1-9). (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - 1928 (December 10-31). (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - 1929 (January 1-7). (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - 1929 (January 8-15). (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - 1929 (January 16-24). (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - 1929 (January 25-31). (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - 1929 (February 1-6). (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 1929 (February 7-19). (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - 1929 (February 20-28). (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - 1929 (March 1-7). (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - 1929 (March 8-15). (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - 1929 (March 16-31). (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - 1929 (April 1-15). (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - 1929 (April 16-30). (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - 1929 (May 1-9). (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - 1929 (May 10-21). (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - 1929 (May 22-31). (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - 1929 (June-August). (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 1929 (September 1-10). (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 1929 (September 11-20). (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 1929 (September 21-30). (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - 1929 (October 1-20). (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - 1929 (October 21-25). (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - 1929 (October 26-31). (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - 1929 (November 1-10). (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - 1929 (November 11-30). (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - 1929 (December). (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - 1930 (January). (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 1930 (February). (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 1930 (March-April). (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - 1930 (May). (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - 1930 (June 1-15). (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - 1930 (June 16-30). (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - 1930 (July). (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - 1930 (August 1-25). (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - 1930 (August 26-31). (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - 1930 (September 1-20). (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - 1930 (September 21-30). (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - 1930 (October). (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - 1930 (November). (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - 1930 (December). (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - 1931 (January-February). (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - 1931 (March). (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - 1931 (April-May). (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - 1931 (June). (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - 1931 (July). (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - 1931 (August). (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - 1931 (September). (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - 1931 (October). (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - 1931 (November-December). (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - 1932 (January-April). (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - 1932 (May). (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - 1932 (June). (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - 1932 (July). (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - 1932 (August). (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - 1932 (September). (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - 1932 (October). (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - 1932 (November-December). (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - 1933 (January-April). (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - 1933 (May). (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - 1933 (June-July). (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - 1933 (August-October). (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - 1933 (November). (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - 1933 (December). (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - 1934 (January-June). (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - 1934 (July-August). (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - 1934 (September-October). (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - 1934 (November). (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - 1934 (December). (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - 1935 (January). (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - 1935 (February-March). (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - 1935 (April-June). (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - 1935 (July). (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - 1935 (August). (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - 1935 (September-October). (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - 1935 (November-December). (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - 1936 (January-March). (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - 1936 (April). (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - 1936 (May-June). (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - 1936 (August-September). (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - 1936 (October). (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - 1936 (November-December). (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - 1937 (January). (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - 1937 (February). (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - 1937 (March 1-5). (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - 1937 (March 6-8). (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - 1937 (March 9-31). (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - 1937 (April). (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - 1937 (May). (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - 1937 (June-July). (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - 1937 (August). (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - 1937 (September-December). (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - 1938 (January-February). (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - 1938 (March). (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - 1938 (April). (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - 1938 (May). (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - 1938 (June). (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - 1938 (July 1-14). (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - 1938 (July 15-31). (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - 1938 (August). (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - 1938 (September-November). (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - 1938 (December). (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - 1939 (January-April). (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - 1939 (May-September). (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - 1939 (October-December). (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - 1940 (January-March). (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - 1940 (April-June). (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - 1940 (July-September). (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - 1940 (October-December). (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - 1941 (January-March). (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - 1941 (April-June). (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - 1941 (July-September). (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - 1941 (October-December). (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - 1942. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - 1943. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - 1944. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - 1945 (January-March). (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - 1945 (April). (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - 1945 (May-June). (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - 1945 (July-December). (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - 1946 (January-June). (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - 1946 (July-December). (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - 1947. (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - 1948. (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - 1949 (January-April). (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - 1949 (May). (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - 1949 (June). (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - 1949 (July-December). (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - 1950. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - 1951 (January-July). (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - 1951 (August-September). (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - 1951 (October-December). (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - 1952 (January-April). (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - 1952 (May-September). (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - 1952 (October-December). (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - 1953 (January-March). (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - 1953 (April-June). (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - 1953 (July-December). (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - 1954 (January-April). (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - 1954 (May-September). (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - 1954 (October-December). (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - 1955 (January-March). (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - 1955 (April-June). (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - 1955 (July-September). (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - 1955 (October-December). (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - 1956 (January-May). (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - 1956 (June-August). (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - 1956 (September-December). (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - 1957 (January-July). (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - 1957 (August-December). (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - 1958 (January-April). (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - 1958 (May-August). (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - 1958 (September-December). (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - 1959 (January-July). (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - 1959 (August-December). (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - 1960. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - 1961. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - 1962. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - 1963. (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - 1964. (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - 1965. (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - 1966-1969. (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - 1970-1973. (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - n.d. (To Bouldin MacLean Crowder). (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - n.d. (To Eleanor Marian Crowder). (Box 19, Folder 2-3)
  - n.d. (To Elizabeth Bouldin Crowder). (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - n.d. (To Elizabeth McLean Crowder). (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - n.d. (From Bouldin MacLean Crowder). (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - n.d. (From Eleanor Marian Crowder). (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - n.d. (From Elizabeth Bouldin Crowder). (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - n.d. (From Elizabeth McLean Crowder). (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - n.d. (From A. Belle McLean). (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - n.d. (From Louis N. Moore). (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - n.d.. (Box 19, Folder 12)
- Series II. Subject Files, 1876-1976., Extent: 10 boxes. (Box 20-29)
  The subject files contain a variety of materials, including accounts and receipts, calling cards, church bulletins, clippings, diaries, estate papers of Alma Bouldin, and Ennis and Robert Puryear, greeting cards, insurance papers, invitations, photographs, programs, school exercises, notes, and examinations, tax records, papers relating to property owned in Vienna, Virginia, and other items.
  - ABC Price List, 16 July 1937. (Box 37)
  - Account and Memorandum Book, 1944-1959. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Accounts and Receipts, 1906, 1912. (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Accounts and Receipts, 1920-1929. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Accounts and Receipts, 1930-1939. (Box 20, Folder 4-6)
  - Accounts and Receipts, 1940-1949. (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Accounts and Receipts, 1950-1959. (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Accounts and Receipts, 1960-1975. (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Accounts and Receipts, n.d.. (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Admission Tickets. (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Amelia County Garden Tour, 1970. (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Artwork, Crafts, etc.. (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Astrological Character Analysis - April 8. (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Autograph Album, 1925. (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Automobile Registrations. (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Aviation Institute. (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Bain-Kimball Company - Monuments and Tombstones. (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Bank Book, 1931. (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Bedford Pedigree. (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Birth Announcements. (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Blotters. (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Broadsides. (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Brochures. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Buggs Island Dam and Reservoir Project, 1948. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Bulletin of Missionary News, 1932-1933. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Business and Trade Cards. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Calendars. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Calling Cards. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Certificate - American Registry of Radiological Technicians, 1936. (Box 37)
  - Certificate - Promotion to High School, 1924. (Box 37)
  - Certificates. (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Checkbook Registers, 1955-1957. (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Church Bulletins. (Box 21, Folder 9-10)
  - Civil Service Examinations, 1936. (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Civil Works Administration. (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Clarksville - Report on Examination, 31 July 1940. (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Class Notes - Biology. (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Clippings. (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - College of William and Mary. (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Community Choral Society of Framingham. (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Contact (Card Game). (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Crowder v. Crowder. (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Crowder, Elizabeth McLean. (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Crowder Guest Home. (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Daily Planner, 1959. (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Deed Abstracts. (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Deeds. (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Diary (Trip to Richmond Carnival), 1900. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Diary (Elizabeth Bouldin Crowder), 1923. (Box 22, Folder 2-3)
  - Diary (Elizabeth Bouldin Crowder), 1924. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Diary (Elizabeth Bouldin Crowder), 29 March - 5 April 1925. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Directory of Hotels, Restaurants, etc.. (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Drewry, Patrick H.. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Elyria Memorial Hospital (Ohio). (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Equitable Life Assurance Society, 1934. (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Estate of Alma Bouldin. (Box 22, Folder 10-14)
  - Estate of Angelina B. Crowder. (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Estate of Ennis Puryear. (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Estate of Robert Puryear. (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Fabric Swatch. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Federated Hardware Mutuals. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Food and House Accounts, 1946-1949. (Box 23, Folder 3-4)
  - Framingham Garden Club. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Framingham Historical and Natural History Society. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Framingham Swimming Pool Association. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Franklin Simon. (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Greeting Cards - Anniversary. (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Greeting Cards - Birthday. (Box 23, Folder 10-11)
  - Greeting Cards - Christmas. (Box 23, Folder 12-14)
  - Greeting Cards - Easter. (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Greeting Cards - Father's Day. (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Greeting Cards - Get Well. (Box 24, Folder 1-3)
  - Greeting Cards - New Year. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Greeting Cards - Note Cards. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Greeting Cards - Sympathy. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Greeting Cards - Thanksgiving. (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Greeting Cards - Valentine's Day. (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Guest Register, 1949. (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Harlow v. Town of Clarksville. (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Healthatorium (Raleigh, NC). (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Insurance. (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Insurance Policy (Alma Bouldin), 1913. (Box 37)
  - Invitations - Dances, etc.. (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Invitations and Annoucements - Commencements. (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Invitations and Announcements - Weddings, Marriages. (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Laundry Tickets. (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - League of Women Voters of Boston - House Tour, 1962. (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Map of Sumter, SC, n.d.. (Box 37)
  - Marriage Certificate - Moore/Crowder, 12 October 1935. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Massachusetts Fellowship of Congregational Christian Women. (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - McLean, Nellie S.. (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - McRorie's Tourist Guide. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Memberships. (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Memorandum Books. (Box 25, Folder 8-9)
  - Mendelssohn (Children's Workbook). (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 25, Folder 11-14)
  - Moore v. Moore et als.. (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Mortgage and Deed - Vienna. (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Morton Hospital (Taunton, Massachussets). (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Newsletters. (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Notes Due and Past Due, 1953-1954. (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Obituaries. (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Olson Rug Company. (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Pacific Mutual Life Insurance. (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Peoples Oil Company, 1966-1967. (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Photographs. (Box 26, Folder 5-6)
  - Plymouth Church in Framingham Centre. (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Poetry/Music. (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Postcards. (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Price Lists. (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Programs - Business and Professional. (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Programs - Cat and Horse Shows. (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Programs - Church, Religious. (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Programs - Community Choral Society of Framingham. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Programs - Concerts. (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Programs - County Playhouse, Framingham. (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Programs - Framingham Union Hospital Aid Association. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Programs - Garden Clubs. (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Programs - Miscellaneous. (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Programs - Schools. (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Programs - Women's Clubs. (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Promissory Notes. (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Recipes. (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Religious Writings. (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Report Cards. (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Riddles, Puzzles, Jokes. (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Russell, John W.. (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - St. Regis Paper Company. (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - School Exercises and Examinations. (Box 28, Folder 1-7)
  - Sex Education Literature. (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Stationary. (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Strayer College. (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Tax Tickets, Receipts, Forms. (Box 28, Folder 11-12)
  - Teasley's A.A. Cottage Camp (Blythe, GA). (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Telephone Directory (Chase City, Barnesville, Boydton, CLarksville, Keysville), 1967. (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Thalhimers. (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Tobacco Sales. (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Toombs, Howard - Tobacco. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Vienna, 1959-1974. (Box 29, Folder 2-17)
  - Virginia Annual Conference. (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Virginia College. (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute Dance, 1930. (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - War Rations. (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Wilcox School of Composition. (Box 29, Folder 22)
  - Woman's Club - Minutes. (Box 29, Folder 23)
  - Woman's Missionary Society. (Box 29, Folder 24)
  - The World Outlook. (Box 29, Folder 25)
  - Yale University. (Box 29, Folder 26)
- Series III. Crowder Brothers Store Records, 1912-1954., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 30-32)
  Crowder Brothers was a retail clothing and general store owned and operated by Bouldin Crowder and John Nelson Crowder (1877-1944), located in downtown Clarksville, Virignia. The records cover the period 1912 to 1954, and include accounts and receipts, a bank book, business and trade cards, correspondence (mostly regarding accounts, orders, and notes past due), insurance papers, leases, promissory notes, sales literature, and tax records. There also various ledgers containing store inventories, purchases, sales, expense accounts, materials and supplies, and payrolls.
  - Accounts and Receipts, 1918-1919. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Accounts and Receipts, 1920-1929. (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Accounts and Receipts, 1930-1932. (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Accounts and Receipts, 1933-1934. (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Accounts and Receipts, 1935-1939. (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Accounts and Receipts, 1941, 1945. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Accounts and Receipts, 1946. (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Accounts and Receipts, 1947. (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Accounts and Receipts, n.d.. (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Bank Book, 1938-1944. (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Business and Trade Cards. (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1917-1919. (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1920-1922. (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1923-1924. (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1927-1928. (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1929. (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1930-1932. (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1933 (January-February). (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1933 (March). (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1933 (April-May). (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1933 (July-December). (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1934-1935. (Box 31, Folder 4)